（忆往昔）
怎么样 我们一起去杀些凶鬼恶灵
So what do you say we kill some evil sons of bitches.
惹点麻烦吧
And we raise a little hell?
你要拿自己的灵魂换吗
You're offering up your own soul?
你只需要复活萨姆
All you gotta do is bring Sam back.
他们给了你多久
How long they give you?
一年
One year.
你死定了
You're gonna die,
这就是你将变成的模样
and this is what you're gonna become.
我不想下地狱
I don't wanna go to hell.
我们会想办法救你的
We'll find a way to save you.
1835年
Back in 1835,
萨穆埃尔·柯尔特造了把枪
Samuel Colt made a gun.
这枪能杀任何东西
This gun can kill anything.
她真名叫贝拉·塔伯特
Bela Talbot's her real name.
她是猎人吗
Is she a hunter?
才不是呢
Pretty frigging far from a hunter.
柯尔特枪
The Colt.
贝拉偷了柯尔特枪
Bela stole the Colt.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
- 帮什么 - 萨姆
- Help with what? - With Sam.
你需要帮我为他做好准备
You need to help me get him ready.
独自扛起战争
to fight this war on his own.
（如今）
起床啦 萨姆
Rise and shine, Sammy.
哥们 亚洲乐队吗
Dude. Asia?
得了 你喜欢这歌 你很清楚
Come on. You love the song, and you know it.
嗯
Yeah,
如果让我再听一遍 我一定自杀
and if I ever hear it again, I'm gonna kill myself.
什么 抱歉 听不到
What? I'm sorry. I can't hear you.
就等你了 迪恩
Whenever you're ready, Dean.
你的吗
This yours?
找到了
Bingo.
谁想去吃早餐了
Now, who's ready for some breakfast?
安全驾驶哦 皮克特先生
Drive safely now, Mr. Pickett.
嗯嗯
Yeah, yeah.
上菜
Order up.
不点单就不能待在这里 卡尔
Can't stay unless you order something, Cal.
你清楚规矩
You know the rules.
来点咖啡
Some coffee.
周二 瞎买猪
Tuesday. Pig in a poke.
你知道那是什么吗
You even know what that is?
- 你们准备好点单了吗 - 嗯
- Are you boys ready? - Yes.
我要特色菜 来点培根 还有咖啡
I'll have the special, side of bacon and coffee.
我也要咖啡 还有松饼
Make it two coffees and a short stack.
好嘞
You got it.
相信我 萨姆 这案子不值一提
I'm telling you, Sam, this job is small fry.
我们应该去找贝拉
We should be spending our time hunting down Bela.
好啊 我们这就去吧
Okay, sure, let's get right on that.
- 她在哪来着 - 闭嘴
- Where is she again? - Shut up.
相信我 我跟你一样想找到她
Look, believe me, I wanna find her as bad as you do.
但现在 我们有这个
In the meantime, we have this.
好 这个教授
All right, so this professor…
戴克斯特·哈索贝克 上周经过了这里
Dexter Hasselback, he was passing through town last week.
然后就消失了
when he vanished.
最后已知地点
Last known location?
他女儿说 他当时正要去
His daughter says he was on his way.
布劳沃德郡的神秘地点
to visit the Broward County Mystery Spot.
「物理规则失去意义的地方」
"Where the laws of physics have no meaning"?
两杯黑咖啡
Two coffees. Black…
好
Okay.
还有辣酱 蘸…
And some hot sauce for the…
该死
Crap.
抱歉
Sorry.
来收拾
Clean up!
萨姆 你知道这种地方就是骗游客的吧
Sam, you know joints like this are only tourist traps, right?
什么球滚上坡
I mean, you know, balls rolling uphill,
家具钉在天花板上
furniture nailed to the ceiling.
- 唯一危险的也就是你的钱包 - 好吧
- The only danger is to your wallet. - Okay. Look.
我就是说 这世上有些地方
I'm just saying, there are spots in the world.
有裂开的洞口 吞噬人类
where holes open up, and swallow people.
百慕大三角 俄勒冈州旋涡
The Bermuda Triangle, the Oregon Vortex.
布劳沃德郡神秘地点吗
Broward County Mystery Spot?
有时 这种地方是真的
Well, sometimes these places are legit.
好吧 如果是真的 这还很难说
All right. So if it is legit, and that's a bigass "if."
那相关传说是什么
What's the lore?
那…
Well, the…
不好意思
Excuse me.
传说其实都很疯狂
The lore's freaking nuts, actually.
据说 这种地方的电磁场很强烈
They say these places, the magnetic fields are so strong…
所以能扭曲时间空间
that they can bend space-time,
把受害人送去…不知哪里
sending victims… no one knows where.
嗯 我觉得听上去太《X档案》了
Yeah. Sounds a little X-Files to me.
我就说塞不进去
I told you it wouldn't fit.
怎么 你想要个普利策新闻奖吗
What do you want, a Pulitzer?
好吧 我不是说这是真的
All right. Look, I'm not saying this is really happening.
但如果是 我们该去看看
But if it is, we gotta check it out.
看能不能做点什么
See if we can do something.
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
我们今晚等关门后过去
We'll go tonight after they close,
好好慢慢地看看那里
get ourselves a nice, long look.
离奇啊
Uncanny.
有发现吗
Find anything?
没有
No.
你知道你要找什么吗
Do you have any idea what you're looking for?
嗯
Yeah.
不知道
No.
你们在这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我们可以解释
We can explain.
你们要抢劫我吗
You robbing me?
听着 没人要抢劫 冷静
Look, nobody's robbing you. Calm down.
好 别动
Okay. Don't move. Don't move.
我就是把枪放下
I'm just putting the gun down.
迪恩
Dean.
快报警
Call 911.
我不是有意的
I… I didn't mean to…
快
Now!
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
不能像这样
Not like this.
迪恩
Dean.
[邪恶力量 第3季第11集]
起床啦 萨姆
Rise and shine, Sammy.
哥们 亚洲乐队
Dude. Asia.
迪恩
Dean.
得了 你喜欢这歌 你很清楚
Come on. You love this song and you know it.
怎么了
What?
我不知道
I don't know.
你没事吧
You all right?
不 我觉得我…
No. I think I…
哥们 我做了个怪梦
Man, I had a weird dream.
是吗 小丑还是侏儒
Yeah? Clowns or midgets?
安全驾驶哦 皮克特先生
Drive safely now, Mr. Pickett.
嗯嗯
Yeah, yeah.
上菜
Order up.
不点单就不能待在这里 卡尔
Can't stay unless you order something, Cal.
你清楚规矩
You know the rules.
咖啡
Coffee.
周二 瞎买猪
Tuesday. Pig in a poke.
今天是周二吗
It's Tuesday?
对
Yeah.
- 你们准备好点单了吗 - 嗯
- Are you boys ready? - Yes.
我要特色菜 来点培根 还有咖啡
I'll have the special, side of bacon and a coffee.
我不用了 谢谢
Nothing for me. Thanks.
你改主意就告诉我
Let me know if you change your mind.
相信我 萨姆 这案子不值一提
I'm telling you, Sam, this job is small fry.
我们应该去找贝拉
We should be spending our time hunting down Bela.
你在听吗
You with me?
什么
What?
你真的感觉还好吗
You sure you feel okay?
你不…
You don't…?
你不记得这一切了吗
You don't remember any of this?
记得什么
Remember what?
这
This.
今天 像是已经发生过了
Today. Like… Like it's happened before?
你是指似曾相识感吗
You mean, like deja vu?
不 像是…
No. I mean, like it's…
像是真的发生过了
Like it's really happened before.
嗯 就是似曾相识嘛
Yeah. Like deja vu.
不 别去想似曾相识了
No. Forget about deja vu.
我是问你 你是否觉得
I'm asking you if it feels like,
我们又重过了一遍昨天
like we're living yesterday all over again?
- 好吧 这怎么不叫似曾… - 别
- Okay, how is that not deja…? - Don't!
别说那个
Don't say it!
别…
Just don't…
黑咖啡 还有辣酱 蘸…
Coffee, black. And some hot sauce for the…
该死
Crap.
谢谢
Thanks.
反应挺快啊
Nice reflexes.
萨姆 抱歉
Sam, I'm sorry but.
我不知道你在说什么呢
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
好吧 听着 昨天是周二 是吧
Okay, look. Yesterday was Tuesday, right?
但今天还是周二
But today is Tuesday too.
嗯 好吧 你绝对没问题
Yeah. No. Good. You're totally balanced.
你不相信我吗
So you don't believe me?
不好意思
Excuse me.
我就是说 这太疯狂了
Look, I'm just saying that it's crazy, you know?
即便对我们来说也太疯狂了
I mean, even-for-us crazy.
澳洲野犬吃了我的孩子那么疯狂
Dingo-ate-my-baby crazy.
或许这又是你的灵力预知
Maybe it was another one of your psychic premonitions.
不 不会 太逼真了
No. No way. Way too vivid.
好吧 听着 我们去了神秘地点 然后
Okay, look. We were at the Mystery Spot, and then…
然后什么
And then what?
然后我就醒过来了
Then I woke up.
我就说塞不进去
I told you it wouldn't fit.
怎么 你想要个普利策新闻奖吗
What do you want, a Pulitzer?
等等 神秘地点 你说会不会…
Wait a minute. The Mystery Spot. You think maybe it…
会不会什么
Maybe what?
我们得去那里看看
We gotta check that place out.
- 就信我一把 好吗 - 好吧 好吧
- Look, just go with me on this, okay? - All right, all right.
我们今晚等关门后过去
We'll go tonight, after close,
好好慢慢地看看那里
get ourselves a nice long look.
等等 什么
Wait. What?
不
No.
为什么不
Why not?
我们现在就去吧 马上去
Let's just go now. Right now.
现在正在营业 人多
Business hours. Nice and crowded.
天啊 你真怪
My God, you're a freak.
迪恩
Dean…
好啦
Okay.
随你了
Whatever.
我们这就去
We'll go now.
迪恩
Dean!
迪恩 不不
Dean. No. No. No.
醒醒 迪恩
Come on. Dean.
迪恩
Dean.
起床啦 萨姆
Rise and shine, Sammy.
周二 瞎买猪
Tuesday. Pig in a poke.
好吧 听我说 好吗 迪恩
Okay. Would you listen to me, Dean?
我都要抓狂了
Because I am flipping out.
你们准备好点单了吗
Are you boys ready?
他要特色菜 来点培根 还有黑咖啡
He'll take the special, side of bacon, coffee black.
我不用了 谢谢
Nothing for me. Thanks.
好嘞
You got it.
萨姆 你那么霸道时 我都有点麻了
Sammy, I get all tingly when you take control like that.
别闹了 迪恩
Quit screwing around, Dean.
好吧
Okay.
好
我听着呢
I'm listening.
那么
So… So…
你觉得你陷入了
Now, you think that you're in some kind of a.
- 什么… - 时间循环
- what exactly…? - Time loop.
- 像《土拨鼠之日》 - 对 没错
- Like Groundhog Day. - Yes. Exactly.
就像《土拨鼠之日》
Like Groundhog Day.
你不相信我吗
So you don't believe me?
这有点疯狂 即便对我们来说也太疯狂了
It's a little crazy. I mean, even-for-us crazy.
就像
You know, like…
澳洲野犬吃了我的孩子那么疯狂
Dingo-ate-my-baby crazy?
你怎么知道我要那么说
How'd you know I was gonna say that?
因为你已经说过一次了 迪恩
Because you've said it before, Dean.
我就想跟你说这个
That's my whole point.
黑咖啡 还有辣酱 蘸…
Coffee, black. And some hot sauce for the…
该死
Crap.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 反应挺快啊 - 不是
- Nice reflexes. - No.
我知道这会发生
I knew it was gonna happen.
好吧 听着
Okay, look.
这肯定是有某种解释的
I'm sure that there's some sort of an explanation…
你就信我一把吧 好吗 迪恩
You just gonna have to go with me on this. All right, Dean.
你必须信我 这是你欠我的
You just have to. You owe me that much.
- 冷静 - 别叫我冷静
- Calm down… - Don't tell me to calm down.
我无法冷静
I can't calm down.
我做不到 因为
I can't, because…
因为什么
Because what?
因为你今天会死 迪恩
Because you die today, Dean.
我才不会死 今天不会
I'm not gonna die. Not today.
已经两次了 我眼看你死去
Twice now, I've watched you die.
我做不到
And I can't.
我不要再来一次了 好吗
I won't do it again, okay?
你只能相信我了
You're just gonna have to believe me.
求你
Please.
好吧
All right.
我还是觉得你疯了 但是
I still think you're nuts, but…
好吧 不管怎么回事 我们一起查清
Okay. Whatever this is, we'll figure it out.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我就说塞不进去
I told you it wouldn't fit.
怎么 你想要个普利策新闻奖吗
What do you want, a Pulitzer?
你觉得这个烂俗的骗游客的地方
And you think this cheesy-ass tourist trap.
跟此事有关系吗
has something to do with it?
那里可能是真的
Maybe it's the real deal, you know.
电磁场扭曲了时间空间还是什么的
The magnetic fields bending space-time, or whatever.
我不知道 我觉得这似乎太《X档案》了
I don't know. All seems a little too X-Files for me.
我不知道还要怎么解释 迪恩
Well, I don't know how else to explain it, Dean.
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
我们今晚等关门后过去
We'll go tonight, after they close,
好好慢慢地看看那里
get ourselves a nice, long look.
不不 不行
No, no, no, no, no. We can't.
为什么不
Why not?
因为你…
Because you…
我什么
I what?
我死在了那里吗
I die there?
是被打爆了
Blown away, actually.
好吧 那我们现在去
Okay. Let's go now.
给老子让路
Get out of the way.
怎么 他…
What, did he…?
昨天 是的
Yesterday. Yeah.
然后呢
And?
然后什么
And what?
看上去像电影里那么酷吗
Did it look cool like in the movies?
你失禁了
You peed yourself.
这是当然了
Of course I peed myself.
被车撞了
A man gets hit by a car,
你还指望他能完全控制自己的膀胱吗
you think he has full control over his bladder?
拜托
Come on.
两位 你们不知道我有多感激
Boys, I can't tell you how much I appreciate this.
我们非常需要好报道
We could use all the good ink we can get.
你经营这里多久了 卡皮亚克先生
How long have you owned the place, Mr. Carpiak?
我的家族守护这里的秘密有…
Well, my family's been guarding the secrets here since…
你不会想知道有多久的
you don't wanna know when.
所以如果发生了什么怪事 你肯定知道
So you'd know if anything strange happen?
怪事
Strange?
这里经常发生怪事
Strange happens here all the time.
这是个神秘地点
It's a mystery spot.
那究竟什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
那是…
Well, uh…
「物理规则失去意义的地方」
"It's where the laws of physics have no meaning."
好吧 具体呢
Okay. Like how?
参观一圈吧
Take the tour.
那个失踪的人 戴克斯特·哈索贝克
The guy who went missing, Dexter Hasselback,
他也参观了吗
he take the tour?
等一下
Hold on a minute.
这是什么样的报道
What kind of article is this?
回答问题
Just answer the question.
警方已搜索了这里的每一寸
The police scoured every inch of this place.
他们找不到那人 我也没见过他
They couldn't find that man. I never seen him before.
- 我们是个家族生意 - 听好了
- We're a family establishment. - Listen to me.
这里有古怪的事发生
There's something weird going on here.
你到底知不知道内情
Now, do you know anything about it or not?
好吧 听着
Okay, look.
两位
Guys…
饶了我吧
give me a break.
这地方是我
I bought the joint.
去年3月在法院拍卖上买的 好吗
at a foreclosure auction last March, all right?
我以前是卖保释保证书的
Hell, I used to sell bail bonds.
好了 大侦探 我们去喘口气吧
Okay, Kojak. Let's get some air.
我也不想说
Well, I hate to say it,
但那地方跟我想的一样
but that place is exactly what I thought.
就是鬼扯
It's full of crap.
对 那究竟怎么回事 迪恩
Yeah, so what is it then, Dean?
我们到底撞上什么事了
What the hell is happening to us?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧 我…
All right, let me just…
- 我每天都会死 - 对
- So every day, I die. - Yeah.
这时你便又会醒来 是吗
That's when you wake up again, right?
嗯
Yeah.
那我们就确保我不会死
So let's just make sure I don't die.
如果我能活到明天
If I make it to tomorrow,
那时间循环或许就会中止
then maybe the loop stops.
我们也能查清真相了
and we can figure all this out.
你觉得行吗
Do you think?
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
我们买点外卖 回旅馆去
I say we grab some takeout, head back to the motel,
什么都不做 直到午夜
lay low until midnight.
好 那好
All right, good.
谁想吃中餐
Who wants Chinese?
起床啦 萨姆
Rise and shine, Sammy.
我还是觉得你疯了 但是
I still think you're nuts, but.
不管怎么回事 我们一起查清
whatever this is, we'll figure it out.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么
So…
如果你卡在《土拨鼠之日》里了 为什么呢
if you're stuck in Groundhog Day, why?
是什么在搞鬼
What's behind it?
起初我以为是神秘地点
Well, first I thought it was the Mystery Spot.
现在我不太确定了
Now I'm not so sure.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
我们努力保住你的命
We keep you breathing,
尽量撑到明天
try to make it to tomorrow.
那是我唯一能想到的了
That's the only thing I can think of.
应该不会太难
Shouldn't be too hard.
得了吧
Yeah. Right,
迪恩 我已经看着你死了几次了
Dean, I've watched you die a few times now.
我似乎就是无法阻止
and I can't ever seem to stop it.
没什么是板上钉钉的
Well, nothing's set in stone.
你说我每天都点一样的东西 是吗
You say I order the same thing every day, right?
对 瞎买猪和培根
Yeah. Pig in a poke, side of bacon.
不好意思 亲爱的
Excuse me, sweetheart.
可以把培根换成香肠吗
Can I get sausage instead of bacon?
没问题 亲爱的
Sure thing, hon.
看 这就不一样了
See? Different day already.
如果你和我决定了我不要死
Cause see, if you and I decide that I am not gonna die…
我就不会死
I'm not gonna die.
谢谢
Thank you.
迪恩
Dean.
Dean?
你是说我们都不能去吃早餐吗
You mean, we can't even go out for breakfast?
到了周三你会感谢我的
You'll thank me when it's Wednesday.
随你说吧
Whatever that means.
你觉得这炸玉米饼味道有没有点奇怪
Do these tacos taste funny to you?
大家都好 没人会受伤的 好吗
Everybody's fine. Nobody's gonna get hurt, okay?
萨姆
Sammy?
要不你放下斧子 放了这人吧
Maybe you should drop the ax and let this guy go.
怎么样
What do you say?
这里肯定有问题
Something's gotta be going on here.
我要查个明白
I intend to find out what.
这地方已经被拆得差不多了 哥们
Place is tore up pretty good, dude.
- 消停下来吧 - 不
- Time to give it a rest. - No!
我要把它全拆掉
I'm gonna take it down to studs.
萨姆 够了 把斧子给我
Sammy, that's enough. Give me the ax.
- 别管了 迪恩 - 给我
- Leave it, Dean. - Give it.
不 你给我
No, you give it.
- 不 - 放手
- No. - Let… Let it go!
- 不 - 行了
- No. - Come on…
- 不 迪恩 放开 - 行了你
- No, Dean. Leave it. - Come on…
迪恩
Dean?
不
No.
安全驾驶哦 皮克特先生
Drive safely now, Mr. Pickett.
嗯嗯
Yeah, yeah.
上菜
Order up.
不点单就不能待在这里 卡尔
Can't stay unless you order something, Cal.
你清楚规矩
You know the rules.
咖啡
Coffee.
周二 瞎买猪
Tuesday. Pig in a poke.
那是什么
What are those?
那老头的
The old man's.
相信我 你不希望他开车的
Trust me. You don't want him behind the wheel.
你们准备好点单了吗
You boys ready?
是的
Yes, we are.
我要特色菜 来点培根 还有咖啡
I'll have the special, a side of bacon and coffee.
多莉丝 我想要你
Doris. What I'd like is for you to.
去射箭馆多练习
log in some more hours at the archery range.
你箭术太差了
You're a terrible shot.
- 你怎么知道的 - 猜的
- How do you know that? - Lucky guess.
好吧 所以你觉得你陷入了什么来着
Okay, so you think you're caught in some kinda what again?
时间循环
Time loop.
就像《土拨鼠之日》
Like Groundhog Day.
无所谓 根本无法阻止
It doesn't matter. There's no way to stop it.
天啊 你脾气好坏
Jeez. Aren't you grumpy?
是啊 是的 知道为什么吗
Yeah, I am. You wanna know why?
为什么
Why?
因为这是我连续经历的第一百个周二了
Becuase this is the hundredth Tuesday in a row I've been through.
一直就没停下
and it never stops.
从没有
Ever.
所以是的 我脾气有点坏
So yeah, I'm a little grumpy.
辣酱
Hot sauce.
- 什么 - 黑咖啡
- What? - Coffee, black.
还有辣酱 蘸…
And some hot sauce for the…
该死 谢谢
Crap. Thanks.
- 反应挺快啊 - 我知道这会发生 迪恩
- Nice reflexes. - I knew it was gonna happen, Dean.
我知道要发生的一切
I know everything that's gonna happen.
你才不会知道一切
You don't know everything.
我知道
Yeah. I do.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
猜得好
Nice guess.
不是猜的
It wasn't a guess.
嗯 你会读心
Right, you're a mind reader.
别闹了 萨姆
Cut it out, Sam.
萨姆
Sam.
你觉得自己很逗 但其实只是很幼稚
You think you're being funny, but you're being really childish.
萨姆·温彻斯特化妆
Sam Winchester wears makeup.
萨姆·温彻斯特做爱时会哭
Sam Winchester cries his way through sex.
萨姆·温彻斯特在床边放了把尺
Sam Winchester keeps a ruler by the bed.
每天早上 他醒来时…
And every morning, when he wakes up…
好了 够了
Okay. Enough.
还不止
That's not all.
收银员兰迪
Randy, the cashier?
他在从收银机里揩油
He's skimming from the register.
迈耶斯法官
Judge Meyers?
他晚上会穿一身毛绒兔子装
At night, he puts on a furry bunny outfit.
那边
Over there.
那是卡尔
That's Cal.
他回家的路上会打劫机械师托尼
He's gonna rob Tony the mechanic on the way home.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我想说 我度过了一切可能的周二
My point is I've lived through every possible Tuesday.
我看着你以各种方式死去
I've watched you die every possible way.
我把神秘地点大卸八块 烧为平地
I have ripped apart the Mystery Spot, burnt it down,
试遍了能想到的所有办法救你 但我做不到
tried everything I know to save your life and I can't.
不管我怎么做 你都会死
No matter what I do, you die.
然后我醒过来
And then I wake up.
又是周二了
And then it's Tuesday again.
狗
The dog.
肯定有办法摆脱这循环的
There's gotta be some way out of this.
「我该死的钥匙呢」
"Where's my dang keys?"
我该死的钥匙呢
Where's my dang keys?
「不好意思」
"Excuse me."
不好意思
Excuse me.
她还挺漂亮
She's kind of cute.
我们走过这条街那么多次
All the times we've walked down this street,
我这么做过吗
did I ever do this?
不好意思 小姐
Excuse me, miss?
没有
No.
一百个周二
Hundred Tuesdays,
你都没看过一次她手里拿了什么吗
you never bother to check what she was holding in her hands?
这是那个失踪者吗
This the guy who went missing?
- 对 - 那是他女儿
- Yeah. - That's his daughter back there.
女士
Ma'am?
小姐
Miss?
伙计
Buddy.
需要个朋友吗
Somebody need a friend?
真乖
Good boy…
警方报告称 戴克斯特·哈索贝克是个教授
So the police report says Dexter Hasselback is a professor…
但他还做别的
but that's not all he is.
他做什么
What is he?
我问过他女儿了
I talked to his daughter.
他是个大记者呢
The guy's quite the journalist.
在杂志上写专栏 还写博客
Columns in magazines, a blog.
他写旅游景点
He writes about tourist attractions:
神秘地点 不明飞行物坠毁地点
Mystery spots, UFO crash sites.
以揭穿骗局为乐
Gets his kicks debunking them.
他已经让四个这种地方关门歇业了
I mean, he's already put four of these places out of business.
看
Here.
「戴克斯特·哈索贝克：真相战士」
"Dexter Hassleback: Truth warrior"?
要我说就是自大的笨蛋
More like a pompous schmuck, if you ask me.
是啊 可不是嘛
Yeah. Tell me about it.
我读了他写的所有东西
I mean, I've read everything the guy's ever written.
他那么自以为是 肯定重有千斤
He must've weighed a ton, he was so full of himself.
你哪来的时间做这么多调研
When did you have time to do all this research?
走吧
Come on.
- 怎么了 - 就是…挺好笑的
- What? - Just… It's funny, you know.
这人一辈子
I mean, this guy spends his whole life.
都在贬低神秘地点
crapping on mystery spots and…
结果他消失在了一个里
then he vanishes in one.
还挺诗意的 有点
It's kinda poetic, you know, like…
罪有应得
just deserts.
是啊 是罪有应得
You're right. It is just deserts.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他一百个周二吃的都是枫树糖浆
Guy has maple syrup for the past hundred Tuesdays.
现在突然改吃草莓味儿的了
All of a sudden, he's having strawberry?
自由国家嘛
It's a free country.
都不能自己选糖浆口味了吗
Man can't choose his own syrup?
我们变成了什么样啊
What have we become?
在这家餐馆里不会变
Not in this diner.
在这一天里不会变
Not today.
这地方的一切从来不变
Nothing in this place ever changes.
从不
Ever.
除了我
Except me.
起床啦 萨姆
Rise and shine, Sammy.
所以你觉得你陷入了什么来着
So you think you're caught in some kinda what again?
吃你的早餐
Eat your breakfast.
包里是什么
What's in the bag?
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
或者该说 你是什么
Or should I say what?
天啊 求你别杀我
My God. Please, don't kill me.
萨姆
Sam?
虽然我用了很长时间 但我明白了
It took me a hell of a long time, but I got it.
- 什么 - 是你的手法暴露了你
- What? - It's your M.O. that gave you away.
针对自大混蛋 让他们罪有应得
Going after pompous jerks, giving them their just deserts.
你们就喜欢那个 是吧
Your kind loves that, don't they?
嗯 好吧 行
Yeah, sure. Okay.
把木桩放下
Just put the stake down.
- 萨姆 或许你该… - 不
- Sam, maybe you should… - No!
只有一种生物
There's only one creature.
有能力做到你做的这些事
powerful enough to do what you're doing.
凭空捏造现实 把人塞进时间循环里
Making reality out of nothing, sticking people in time loops.
事实上 你差不多得是个神了
In fact, you'd pretty much have to be a god.
你得是个恶作剧精灵
You'd have to be a trickster.
先生 我叫爱德·科曼
Mister, my name is Ed Coleman.
我妻子叫艾米莉娅 我有两个孩子
My wife's name's Amelia. I got two kids.
老天爷啊 我是卖广告位的
For crying out loud, I sell ad space.
别骗我 我知道你是什么
Don't lie to me! I know what you are.
我们杀过一个你的同类
We've killed one of your kind before.
其实 伙计 你没杀过
Actually, bucko, you didn't.
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
你开玩笑呢吧
You're joking, right?
你们俩蠢蛋上次企图杀我
You chuckleheads tried to kill me last time.
我干吗不这么做
Why wouldn't I do this?
还有哈索贝克 他呢
And Hasselback. What about him?
那蠢蛋
That putz?
他说他不相信虫洞
He said he didn't believe in wormholes,
我就把他丢进了一个虫洞
so I dropped him in one.
然后你们就来了
Then you guys showed up.
你们一来 我就发现你们了
I made you the second you hit town.
这对你来说很好玩吗
So this is fun for you?
一遍遍杀死迪恩
Killing Dean over and over again?
一 是的 是好玩
One, yes, it is fun.
二
And two,
这才不是为了杀迪恩
this is so not about killing Dean.
这玩笑是针对你的 萨姆
This joke is on you, Sam.
每天眼看着你哥哥死去
Watching your brother die every day.
直到永远
Forever.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
你要多久才能明白
How long will it take you to realize…
你救不了你哥哥
you can't save your brother.
不管你怎么做
no matter what?
是吗
Yeah?
我杀了你 一切就马上结束了
I kill you, this all ends now.
好吧 听着
Okay. Okay. Look.
我只是玩玩罢了
I was just playing around.
你开不起玩笑 好啊
You can't take a joke? Fine.
你可以解脱了
You're out of it.
明天 你醒来 就是周三了
Tomorrow, you wake up, it'll be Wednesday.
我发誓
I swear.
你撒谎
You're lying.
如果是 你知道去哪找我
If I am, you know where to find me.
在餐馆吃松饼
Having pancakes at the diner.
不 还是杀了你更简单
No. Easier to just kill you.
抱歉 小子
Sorry, kiddo.
那可不行
Can't have that.
你打算睡一天吗
Were you gonna sleep all day?
- 没有亚洲乐队 - 是啊
- No Asia. - Yeah, I know.
这电台真烂
This station sucks.
（星期三）
今天是周三
It's Wednesday.
对 一般都是紧接着周二的
Yeah, which usually comes after Tuesday.
把那玩意关了 好吗
Turn that thing off, would you?
什么 你开玩笑吗
What, are you kidding?
这难道不是你听过的最美妙的歌吗
This isn't the most beautiful song you've ever heard?
不是
No.
天啊 你过了多少个周二
Jeez. How many Tuesdays did you have?
我不知道 我数不过来了
I don't know. I lost count.
等等 你记得什么
Wait. What do you remember?
我记得你昨天很疯狂
I remember you were pretty wacked out of it yesterday,
然后我记得我们碰到了恶作剧精灵
then I remember running into the trickster.
但再就没别的了
But no, that's about it.
好吧
All right.
收拾东西 我们马上离开这里 现在就走
Pack your stuff. Let's get the hell out of town. Now.
不吃早餐吗
No breakfast?
不吃早餐
No breakfast.
你确定我们就这么放过恶作剧精灵吗
Are you sure we should just let the trickster go?
把你的钱包给我
Give me your wallet.
伙计 放松
Buddy. Just relax.
我挺放松的
I am relaxed.
好 好吧
Okay. All right.
没人希望事情往坏的方向发展
Nobody wants this to end the wrong way.
我们谈谈吧
Let's talk about it a sec.
迪恩
Dean!
不不不
No. No, no, no, no, no.
别 今天不该这样
Come on. Not today. Not today.
今天不该发生这种事了 醒醒
This isn't supposed to happen today. Come on.
我该醒过来的
I'm supposed to wake up.
（六个月后）
是萨姆 给我留言
It's Sam. Leave me a message.
萨姆 是鲍比
Sam, it's Bobby.
听说你在死亡谷干掉的那个恶魔了
Heard about that demon thing you took care of in Death Valley.
好样的
Nice job.
但我们都三个月没联系了
It's been about three months we talked, though.
我真想听到你的声音
It'd be nice to hear your voice.
给我打电话 我就在这里
Give a call. I'm here.
萨姆 还是鲍比
Sam? Bobby again.
听着 我担心你
Look, I'm worried about you.
告诉我你没一个人坐在哪里
Just tell me you're not sitting alone somewhere…
执迷于找恶作剧精灵
obsessing over this damn trickster.
打给我 萨姆
Call me, Sam.
我们可以一起找他
We can find it together.
没人该独自面对那样的怪物
No one man should take something like this on alone.
听到了吗
Do you hear me?
对了 奥斯丁那个吸血鬼血巢 真厉害
By the way, that vampire nest in Austin, hell of a job.
萨姆 是鲍比
Sam? It's Bobby.
我找到他了
I found him.
见到你真好 孩子
It's good to see you, boy.
我们为什么来这里 鲍比
What are we doing here, Bobby?
这是我们能确定的最后一个
Well, this is the last place we're sure.
恶作剧精灵曾施展魔法的地方
the trickster worked his magic.
所以呢
So?
所以你想抓到他
So you want this thing?
我找到个召唤仪式 能把恶作剧精灵引来
I found a summoning ritual to bring the trickster here.
我们需要什么
What do we need?
血
Blood.
多少血
How much blood?
仪式需要近一加仑
Ritual says near a gallon.
而且要新鲜的
And it's gotta be fresh too.
你是说我们得流干一个人的血
Meaning we have to bleed a person dry.
而且必须是今晚 否则
And it's gotta be tonight, or.
就要再等50年了
not for another 50 years.
那我们去找血吧
Then let's go get some.
你真让我心碎 孩子
You break my heart, kid.
什么
What?
我才不会允许你杀个无辜者
I'm not gonna let you murder an innocent man.
那你为什么带我来这里
Then why did you bring me here?
为什么
Why?
因为这是唯一能让你来见我的办法
Because it was the only way you'd see me.
因为我想让你恢复理智
Because I'm trying to knock some sense into you.
因为我以为你不会考虑杀人
Because I thought you'd back down from killing a man.
那你想错了
Well, you thought wrong.
留下东西 我自己做
Leave the stuff. I'll do it myself.
我说了 我不会允许你杀人的
I told you, I'm not gonna let you kill anyone.
我做什么与你无关
It's none of your damn business what I do!
你要是那么想要回你哥哥
You want your brother back so bad…
好啊
fine.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
杀我 总比杀个平民好
Better me than a civilian.
你疯了 鲍比 我才不会杀你
You're crazy, Bobby. I'm not killing you.
现在还成我疯了吗
Now I'm the crazy one.
听着 萨姆
Look, Sam.
我老了 我的人生快结束了
I'm old. I'm coming near the end of my trail.
但你还能继续战斗 救人
But you can keep fighting, saving folks.
但你需要你哥哥
But you need your brother.
所以让我帮你救回他吧
So let me give him back to you.
鲍比
Bobby…
你和迪恩
You and Dean, you…
你们是我最接近家人的人了
You boys are the closest thing I have to family.
我想这么做
I wanna do this.
好
Okay.
那好
Good.
利索点吧
Just make it quick.
动手吧 孩子
Do it, son.
嗯 好 鲍比
Yeah, okay, Bobby.
但你知道为什么吗
But you wanna know why?
因为你不是鲍比
Because you're not Bobby.
鲍比
Bobby?
Bobby.
鲍比
Bobby!
你是对的
You're right.
我就是骗你玩呢
I was just screwing with you.
但真不错啊 萨姆
Pretty good, though, Sam.
真聪明
Smart.
告诉你
Let me tell you.
说迪恩是心理有问题的那个兄弟的人
Whoever said Dean was the dysfunctional one…
是没见过你手里拿着尖利物体的样子
has never seen you with a sharp object in your hands.
简直是全金属外壳
Holy Full Metal Jacket.
复活他
Bring him back.
谁 迪恩吗
Who, Dean?
我的姑娘没送花给你吗
Didn't my girl send you the flowers?
迪恩死了
Dean's dead.
他不会复活了
He ain't coming back.
他的灵魂这会儿正在楼下跳地狱烈火伦巴呢
His soul's downstairs doing the hellfire rumba as we speak.
带我们回到那个周二
Just take us back to that Tuesday.
或者周三 一切开始的时候 求你
Or Wednesday, when it all started, please.
我们不会来找你的 我发誓
We won't come after you. I swear.
你发誓
You swear?
是的
Yes.
我不知道
I don't know.
即便我能
Even if I could…
- 你能 - 不假
- You can. - True.
但那不代表我该那么做
But that don't mean I should.
萨姆
Sam…
这里有个教训
there's a lesson here.
我一直努力想灌输进
that I've been trying to drill into that.
你那颗怪异的克鲁马努人的脑袋里
freakish, Cro-Magnon skull of yours.
教训
Lesson?
什么教训
What lesson?
你对拯救迪恩的执迷
This obsession to save Dean?
你俩不断地为彼此牺牲
The way you two keep sacrificing yourselves for each other?
这不会有好结果
Nothing good comes out of it.
只有鲜血和痛苦
Just blood and pain.
迪恩是你的弱点
Dean's your weakness.
坏人也知道
The bad guys know it too.
他会害死你的 萨姆
He's gonna be the death of you, Sam.
有时 你得对人放手
Sometimes you just gotta let people go.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
是啊
Yup.
不管怎样
And like it or not…
这就是失去他之后的人生
this is what life's gonna be like without him.
求你
Please.
就…
Just…
求你了
Please.
我发誓 简直像对牛弹琴
I swear, it's like talking to a brick wall.
好吧 听着
Okay, look.
这一切几个月前就不再好玩了
This all stopped being fun months ago.
你简直是穿短裙的出租车司机 伙计
You're Travis Bickle in a skirt, pal.
我受够了
I'm over it.
什么意思
Meaning what?
意思是 我明白
Meaning, that's for me to know…
你自己琢磨吧
and you to find out.
你打算睡一天吗
Were you gonna sleep all day?
我知道 没有亚洲乐队
I know. No Asia.
这电台真烂
This station sucks.
（星期三）
今天是周三
It's Wednesday.
对 一般都是紧接着周二的
Yeah. Which usually follows Tuesday.
把那玩意关了
Turn that thing off.
哥们 你过了多少个周二
Dude, how many Tuesdays did you have?
够多了
Enough.
等等
Wait.
你记得什么
What do you remember?
我记得你昨天很疯狂
I remember you were pretty wacked out yesterday.
我记得抓到恶作剧精灵
I remember catching up with the trickster.
再就没别的了
That's about it.
我们走
Let's go.
不吃早餐吗
No breakfast?
不吃早餐
No breakfast.
好吧 我去收拾车
All right. I'll pack the car.
等等 你别想一个人去任何地方
Wait. You're not going anywhere alone.
就是停车场而已 萨姆
It's the parking lot, Sam.
就…
Just…
相信我
Just trust me.
你看上去不太好 还发生什么事了吗
You don't look so good. Something else happen?
我就是做了个很怪的梦
I just had a really weird dream.
小丑还是侏儒
Clowns or midgets?